CHRISTINA TIPPING

209 EAST LINCOLN STREET, MEDIA, PA 19063

610-566-8689 • tips2004@verizon.net

Profile

Dedicated and enthusiastic special education teacher with 12+ years of experience in Approved Private Schools. Successful in providing lessons that align with state standards, meet the individual needs of the students, and creating adapted materials that are engaging and are best suited to students' abilities. Extensive experience assisting with the development and implementation of behavioral and therapeutic techniques, including but not limited to, the theories of applied behavior analysis (ABA), positioning students, sensory techniques, and both low and high-tech augmentative alternative communication (AAC).

Education

Widener University
1998 • Bachelor of Arts

Major: Humanities; Concentration: Elementary Education

Cabrini College
In Progress • Masters in Special Education
(24 credits completed)

Certification

Instructional 1: K-6, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, issued January 1999

Instructional 1: Special Education, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, issued June 2008

Instructional II: K-6 & Special Education N-12, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, issued August 2013

Professional Experience

Classroom Teacher • November 2010–June 2013 C.A.D.E.S. (APS in Swarthmore, PA)

Classroom instructor responsible for teaching 8 students between the ages of 12-17 with multiple disabilities and also responsible for the supervision of 5 individuals: 2 assistants, 2 personal care nurses and one additional staff member who attended to a student with medical and behavioral needs. Daily responsibilities included: writing evaluation reports, conducting annual IEP's, assessingstudent learning and providing progress monitoring updates on IEP goals on a regular basis, preparing lesson plans, maintaining accurate records as required by law, and employing a variety of instructional techniques and instructional media, consistent with the needs and capabilities of the students. Classroom skills focused on Language Arts, Social Studies, Science, Math, classroom communication, sensory integration and daily living. Worked closely with school administrators, classroom staff and therapists to develop effective teaching plans and developed many data collection systems for use in the classroom by working closely with Speech and Language Pathologists to effectively communicate with all students, especially those (2 students) with high tech communication devices.

Floating Teacher • 2006 – 2010 C.A.D.E.S. (APS in Swarthmore, PA)

Floating classroom instructor filling in for various full-time teachers. Duties included: assisting with daily classroom routines, assisting in the evaluation of students with varying disabilities and aiding teachers with lesson planning.

Classroom Teacher • 2000-2006

The Melmark School. (APA in Berwyn, PA)

Classroom instructor responsible for teaching 6 students between the ages of 12-18 with multiple disabilities (Autism, Down Syndrome and Mental Retardation) and supervised/trained numerous Teaching Assistants. Daily responsibilities included: writing evaluation reports, conducting annual IEP's, assessing student learning and providing progress monitoring updates on IEP goals on a regular basis, preparing lesson plans, maintaining accurate records as required by law, and employing a variety of instructional techniques and instructional media, consistent with the needs and capabilities of the students. Classroom skills focused on Social and Leisure Skills, including but not limited to group/peer interaction and toleration, conversational turns, time management skills and social skills for the classroom and community. Additionally, I worked with residential staff on getting programs set up and carried across settings, as well as, behavior analysts to develop more effective IEP's, teaching plans, motivational systems, daily schedules, and Behavior Support Plans to better suit the needs of my students, especially those with intense maladaptive behaviors.

Additional Skills/Accomplishments

- Experience with Picture Exchange Communication Systems
- Experience with Augmentative Communication Devices
- Presentation in 2001 The Use of Antecedent Management, Rule-Governed Behavior and Contingency Management to Decrease Sever Aggressions. Presented at NYSABA 2001 Convention Poster Presentation.
- Participant in Professional Development Pilot Program through Widener University at Lakeview Elementary School, Ridley Park, PA. Chosen to participate in a pilot program consisting of three student teachers. Worked closely with the University Supervisor and the Dean of Education to develop a plan to facilitate student teachers to more easily become an integral part of the classroom environment. The program involved targeting one student for a case study which was developed and presented to the university supervisor, Lakeview's principal, and the other teachers and student teachers involved in the program. Program lasted fourteen weeks in the fall of 1998.

References

- William Benson- Director, C.A.D.E.S. 610-328-5955
- Theresa Tocco-Transition Coordinator, C.A.D.E.S. 610-328-5955
- Jennifer Lisberger- Speech Language Pathologist, C.A.D.E.S. 610-328-5955 ext. 1206
- Cheryl Marmer- Classroom Teacher, C.A.D.E.S. 610-328-5955